Your media player does not support the subtitle format used in this episode. Subtitles will likely not function properly. Please use one of the recommended video players, preferably mpv: https://mpv.io
.مشغل الفيديو الخاص بك لا يدعم صيغة ملف الترجمة المستخدمة في هذه الحلقة .من المحتمل ألا تعمل الترجمة بشكل صحيح يرجى استخدام أحد مشغلات الفيديو :على سبيل المثال mpv الموصى بها، كمشغل https://mpv.io
Your media player does not support the subtitle format used in this episode. Subtitles will likely not function properly. Please use one of the recommended video players, preferably mpv: https://mpv.io
.مشغل الفيديو الخاص بك لا يدعم صيغة ملف الترجمة المستخدمة في هذه الحلقة .من المحتمل ألا تعمل الترجمة بشكل صحيح يرجى استخدام أحد مشغلات الفيديو :على سبيل المثال mpv الموصى بها، كمشغل https://mpv.io
How could this have happened?!
!كيف لهذا أن يحدث
Lady Komurasaki!
كوموراساكي-ساما
I would give anything to see you again!
!لكم أود رؤيتكِ مجددًا
This isn't the oiran's procession I wanted to watch.
هذا ليس موكب الأويران الذي أردت رؤيته
Where are you taking Lady Komurasaki?!
!إلى أين تأخذون كوموراساكي-ساما؟
She defied Shogun Orochi.
لقد تمردت على أوروتشي-ساما
She will receive a criminal's cremation at Rasetsu Prison.
سنحرق جثتها في معقل سجناء بلدة راسيتسو
Tonoyasu's been caught?!
قُبض على تونوياسو؟
What in the world is going on?!
ما الذي يحدث؟
To think Tonoyasu was the Witching Hour Boy!
لا أصدق أنّ تونوياسو-سان هو فتى ساعة السحر
The Witchin Hour Boy...
...فتى ساعة السحر
Night after night, the master thief stole treasures from the rich
اللص الشهير الذي يسرق المال والأغراض من الأغنياء
before distributing them to the poor and the vulnerable.
ويمنحها للفقراء والضعفاء كل ليلة
A thief?!
لص؟
That old fogey?
ذلك العجوز؟
The Witching Hour Boy...
...فتى ساعة السحر
The Flower Capital was abuzz with his name.
سمعت أشخاصًا يتحدثون عنه في عاصمة الزهور
I don't get it. Wasn't he some kind of saint?
لا أفهم ذلك، ظننت أنه كان رجلًا صالحًا
Tonoyasu!
!تونوياسو-سان
Why is everyone laughing?!
لماذا يضحك الجميع؟
Your man is getting crucified!
يوشك رفيقكم أن تُضرب عنقه
Is Tonoyasu really the Witching Hour Boy?!
هل حقًّا تونوياسو-سان هو فتى ساعة السحر؟
Even if it were true, it wouldn't matter.
حتى إن كان ذلك صحيحًا، ذلك ليس الأمر المهم الآن
I remember him! It was that hair.
...تذكرته، تلك التسريحة
Tonoyasu is an alias.
تونوياسو هو اسم مزيف
Then just who is he?
من يكون؟
It looks like something big is going down in the Flower Capital.
يبدو أنّ أمرًا مثيرًا للاهتمام يحدث في عاصمة الزهور
Turn on the light-scroll snail.
شغلوا حلزون لفيفة الضوء
You know him?
هل تعرفه؟
Y-Yes. I know him well.
أجل، أعرفه تمامًا
That gentleman...
...ذلك الرجل
He used to be one of the daimyo who served the Kozuki Clan along with Lord Oden...
كان أحد الدايميو الذين خدموا عشيرة الكوزكي مع أودين-ساما
His true name was...
...اسمه الحقيقي هو
Shimotsuki...
..شيموتسكي
Lord Yasuie!
!ياسويي-دونو
The daimyo of Hakumai! Yasu the Hedgehog!
دايميو هاكوماي، ياسو القنفذ
He was a stern man who never smiled.
كان رجلًا صارمًا لم أره يبتسم أبدًا
I didn't recognize him because he was nothing like his old self!
لم أتعرف عليه لأنه لا يشبه ما كان عليه في الماضي
Stop the execution!
!أوقفوا الإعدام
I'm from Hakumai!
!أنا من هاكوماي
I'm glad I saw you again...!
!سعيدٌ لرؤيتك مجددًا
Release Lord Yasuie now, you damn bureaucrats!
!فكّوا وثاق ياسويي-ساما أيها الأوغاد
Lord Yasuie!
!ياسويي-ساما
The people haven't forgotten me yet?!
لم ينسني الناس إذًا
How delightful!
يسعدني هذا
Hakumai is the only region in Wano with an official port.
هاكوماي هذه هي المنطقة الوحيدة في بلاد وانو التي تضم ميناءً قانونيًّا
It brings both good and bad visitors.
هذا يعني أنها مدخل للأخيار والأشرار
Thus...
...لهذا السبب
we must have an indomitable army.
علينا أن نكون جيشًا منيعًا
I'd expect nothing less from Wano's finest samurai.
كما عهدنا ثلة ساموراي وانو الأقوى
Want a bite?
أتريد قليلًا؟
Are you mocking me, Oden?
كفاك عبثًا يا أودين
Your loitering here is wearisome.
إلى متى ستواصل التسكع هنا؟
At least in name, you are the shogun's son.
لا تنس أنك ابن الشوغن
They threw me out. I'm not sure if they still consider me family.
طردوني، لا أدري هل ما زالوا يعدونني ضمن العائلة أصلًا
Everyone says...
:الجميع يقول
"Oden will not be the heir to Kozuki Sukiyaki...
"وريث كوزكي سوكياكي لن يكون أودين"
It'll be Shogun Yasuie."
"بل سيكون ياسويي"
You idiot!
!أيها الأحمق
Ow!
!مؤلم
What was that for?!
!لِمَ فعلت ذلك؟
Don't take these idle rumors to heart!
لا تأخذ تلك الإشاعات على محمل الجد
You are the one and only successor of the Kozuki Clan!
أنت الرجل الذي سيقود عشيرة الكوزكي
Lord Sukiyaki disowning you was just tough love.
طرد سوكياكي-ساما لك ليس إلا حبًا قاسيًا
Why not show him what he wants?
حاول أن ترتقي لتطلعاته
Yasu.
ياسو-سان
I'd rather try my luck at sea.
أنا أفضّل خوض غمار البحر
Why doesn't this country allow that?
لماذا لا تسمح هذه البلاد بذلك؟
This isolationist policy... I detest these confines!
سياسة العزلة هذه مزعجة
Quiet!
!صمتًا
Only a true samurai is allowed selfish whims!
قل ما يحلو لك بعد أن تصير ساموراي كفؤًا
That hurts! Where do you get off punching me?!
هذا مؤلم، كفّ عن ضربي
Who do you think I am?!
من تظنني في رأيك؟
You're still a nobody. Just some delinquent.
أنت لا تزال نكرة، مجرد جانح لعين
It's no use, my friends! Orochi won't let me go.
لا فائدة يا جماعة، أوروتشي لن يتركني وشأني
But first, there are two things for which I must apologize.
أولًا، أريد الاعتذار للجميع بشأن أمرين
And I also have one thing to say to that fool Orochi!
وهنالك شيء أريد إخباره للمعتوه أوروتشي
Toko!
!توكو
Once I've said my piece, I'll cross to the other side with a smile on my face.
بعدما أقول ما عندي، أستطيع مغادرة هذا العالم ضاحكًا
Daddy!
!أبي
I will now state the charges against the accused.
سأقرأ التّهم الموجهة للمتّهم
This man committed theft in the Flower Capital last night.
البارحة، ارتكب جريمة سرقة في عاصمة الزهور
How the mighty have fallen...
تدهور حال الدايميو السابق لهاكوماي حتى أصبح يكسب رزقه مهرجًا في بلدة إبيسو
His name is Shimotsuki Yasuie!
إنه شيموتسكي ياسويي
For the heinous crime of rebelling against Shogun Orochi in the past,
لقاء جريمة التمرد الفظيعة ضد الشوغن أوروتشي-ساما في الماضي
we present him as an offering to the oiran Komurasaki's grave...
وقربانًا لقبر الأويران كوموراساكي
hereby sentencing him to an ignominious death.
حُكم عليه بالإعدام المخزي
Now, he has confessed...
والآن، حسب شهادته
to being the Witching Hour Boy, a known menace to society.
فإنه كان فتى ساعة السحر الذي سبب المتاعب للعامة
I lied about that!
كنت أكذب
What did you say?!
ما الذي قلته توًّا؟
I figured I was going to die, so I said that to draw attention to myself.
قلتُ ذلك لأنني أردت الحصول على انتباه الكل طالما أنني ميت لا محالة
I'm sorry about lying.
أعتذر لأنني كذبت
I'm not the hero you thought I was.
أنا لست ذلك البطل
Lord Yasuie!
ياسويي-دونو
Why did he tell such a lie?
لِمَ قال كذبة كهذه؟
The sorrow surrounding Komurasaki's funeral has shifted its focus to Yasuie's execution.
الضجة الصادرة من جنازة كوموراساكي قد توجهت إلى إعدام ياسويي
Drake, the Ebisu townspeople are charging into the Flower Capital!
!دريك-سان، إنّ سكان بلدة إبيسو يتوافدون إلى عاصمة الزهور
What?!
ماذا قلت؟
That man appears to be more important than we imagined.
يبدو أنّ هذا الرجل أهم مما كنا نتخيله
You can't die, Yasu!
!لا تمت يا ياسو-سان
Yasu!
!ياسو-سان
We'd be lost without your support!
!إن فقدناك، فمن سيدعمنا غيرك؟
You don't have permission to enter the city! Go back to Ebisu Town, damn peasants!
!لا تدخلوا هذه البلدة دون إذن، عودوا إلى بلدة إبيسو أيها المتسولون
Yasu!
!ياسو-سان
The residents on the main street are raging!
!هنالك اضطرابات بين السكان في الشارع الرئيسي
In the west district, too!
!وفي الحي الغربي أيضًا
One problem after another...
المشكلات تتوالى
Lord Orochi's decision to broadcast the execution via the light-scrolls may backfire.
قرار أوروتشي-ساما ببث الإعدام بحلازين لفائف الضوء عاد بالسوء علينا
Maintain vigilance throughout the city.
راقبوا المناطق الأخرى أيضًا
The lord shogun is incompetent, which means his retainers have their work cut out for them.
الشوغن-دونو مجرد أحمق، أشعر بالأسى على حياة أتباعه الصعبة
Listen, my friends!
اسمعوا جميعًا
Behold, the lovely Flower Capital!
انظروا إلى عاصمة الزهور الجميلة
The view of Wano is simply magnificent!
إنّ منظر بلاد وانو هذا لا نظير له
This landscape is the product of
هذا المشهد أمامكم شيدته أجيال متعاقبة على أيدي عشيرة الكوزكي والمواطنين
We take pride in it.
إنه مصدر سعادتنا وفخرنا
Hurry!
!أسرعوا
Get a move on!
!أسرعوا أكثر
He's started spouting nonsense!
!لقد بدأ يتحدث بالهراء
A fool like you has no right to take credit for this beauty...
لا يمكنك نسب فضل ذلك لنفسك
Kurozumi Orochi!
يا كوروزومي أوروتشي
Can you hear me, Orochi?!
هل تسمعني يا أوروتشي؟
There were once vast forests, grasslands...
كانت هنالك غابات شاسعة وسهول خضراء
rivers...
وأنهار
and villages!
وقرى
You stained it all with your greed-spawned sludge!
وكل ما فعلته هو تلويثها بتراب الجشع
You're nothing but a vermin!
!ما أنت إلا آفة
Damn you!
ذلك اللعين
Damn you, Holdem!
!هولديم الوغد
How dare you set fire to my hideout!
!كيف يجرؤ على إضرام النار في مخبئي؟
Where are you?! Get out here!
!أين أنت؟ اخرج
Holdem!
!هولديم
Is that...?!
...هذا
That's enough, Lord Yasuie!
!هذا يكفي يا ياسويي-ساما
You won't be able to take it back!
!لن تستطيع التراجع عن كلامك هكذا
There is another thing...
...هنالك أمر آخر
that I would like to apologize to you for.
أريد الاعتذار عنه
Regarding the flyer with the symbol that's been making the rounds...
بشأن تلك المنشورات ذات العلامة التي انتشرت مؤخرًا
The Kozuki name's been dead twenty years.
مرّت عشرين سنة منذ اندثر اسم الكوزكي
We no longer have the strength to avenge them.
ولم نستطع جمع ما يكفي من الجنود لتحقيق انتقامنا
I was feeling remorse for the Kozuki Clan...
وكنت أشعر بالسوء حيال عشيرة الكوزكي
so I created that flyer!
لذلك صنعت تلك المنشورات
The symbol is meaningless.
لا يعني الرمز أي شيء
It was...
...إنه
just a prank!
!مجرد مقلب
What the hell's he saying?!
...ما الذي
There you are, Ashura!
ها أنت ذا يا أشورا
Oh, Kin'emon! Inuarashi! This is big!
كينيمون، إينواراشي، لا أصدق الأمر
Look!
انظرا
Lord Yasuie appears to have survived.
يبدو أنّ ياسويي-ساما ما زال حيًّا
Yes, I just found out myself.
أجل، اكتشفت ذلك توًّا أيضًا
It has become quite a spectacle.
الوضع يخرج عن السيطرة
Oden died twenty years ago.
مات أودين قبل عشرين سنة
Orochi spoke to us, the four remaining daimyo.
:وسأل أوروتشي الدايميو الأربعة المتبقين بمن فيهم أنا
"Will you serve under the Kurozumi?
"هل ستخدمون الكوروزومي؟"
Or will you fight us?"
"أم ستقاتلوننا؟"
How laughable!
!يا للأضحوكة
You owed a great debt to Oden,
كانت ديونك لأودين كبيرة
yet you usurped the shogunate through a devious scheme!
مع ذلك استوليت على منصب الشوغن بالمكر والخداع
Who would acknowledge you?!
من ذا الذي يعترف بك؟
The daimyo and people from each region immediately took up arms.
استلّ الدايميو والسكان من كل مقاطعة سيوفهم دونما تردد
We were unfortunately routed by the monster known as Kaido,
لكن اعترض طريق انتقامنا الوحش المسمى كايدو
so Wano was consumed in flames.
وغرقت بلاد وانو في ألسنة اللهب
I reluctantly survived and hid away in Ebisu Town.
ورغم أنها لم تكن نيتي إلا أنني نجوت وعشت في بلدة إبيسو سرًّا
However, it'd be a shame to die a natural death...
ومع ذلك، سيكون من العار أن أموت بسبب الشيخوخة
So, channeling my inner child, I came up with the idea for the flyer prank and gave it a shot.
لذلك نسقت هذه الحيلة الطفولية برسم المنشورات
I hope you can forgive me.
اعذروني من فضلكم
Nevertheless, Orochi's cowardice surpassed all expectations.
لكن أوروتشي كان جبانًا أكثر مما ظننت
He seems to have imprisoned innocent people simply because of a popular moon tattoo.
أصيب بالذعر وسجن أبرياء لمجرد أنّ لديهم وشم هلال
Was it all in Shogun Orochi's mind?!
أكان أوروتشي-ساما يتخيل الخطر بسبب ذعره؟
What should we do?! We've arrested so many!
!ماذا نفعل؟ لقد أمسكنا كثيرًا منهم
Shogun Orochi! It's in sight now!
!أوروتشي-ساما، أنا أراه
You bastard, Yasuie!
!عليك اللعنة يا ياسويي
Just wait till I fill you with lead!
!سأرديك بالرصاص
There you are.
ها قد أتيت
Long time no see, Orochi.
أوروتشي، لم أرك منذ مدة
Any last words, Yasuie?!
!هل من كلمات أخيرة يا ياسويي؟
Orochi! I suppose I do...
...أوروتشي، لنرَ
Shall I recite the curse that has haunted you?
هل أخبرك باللعنة التي تقيّد قلبك؟
"A man of such small caliber shall never know...
رجل قليل الحيلة
the taste of oden in all of his life!"
سيكبده أودين معاناة ليست بالقليلة
Well, that's it.
هذه هي نهايتي
Go forth... Kin'emon and the Red Scabbards.
تعرفون ما العمل يا كينيمون والأغماد التسعة
You too, Momonosuke, the future shogun.
وأيها الشوغن المستقبلي مومونوسكي
This effectively resets your plan!
عادت خطتكم الآن للعمل
I provided a new rendezvous point...
...أعطيتُ حلفاءكم الذين اعتقلوا في بلدة راسيتسو
for our comrades imprisoned in Rasetsu Town.
نقطة لقاء جديدة
I know it's not much, but there's nothing more I can do with this life of mine.
هذا ليس بالكثير، لكنه كل ما أستطيع فعله بحياتي
Is he going to sacrifice himself to keep our plan alive?!
هل يحاول التضحية بنفسه لإبقاء خطتنا تعمل؟
Lord Yasuie!
...ياسويي-دونو
We are forever in your debt!
نحن مدينون لك
No matter how much that coward Orochi hollers,
مهما كان ما سيصرخ به الجبان أوروتشي
his soldiers will no longer be swayed.
سيشكّ جنوده بأوامره
A shogun shouldn't act with such fear.
سئمت من ذعر الشوغن هذا
Stop it! They'll hear you!
توقف، سيسمعك شخص ما
Daddy!
!أبي
Yasu!
!ياسو
For twentyh years, no one could chop off Kaido's head!
لم يتمكن أحد من الإطاحة بكايدو طوال العشرين سنة
But this time...!
...لكن هذه المرة
Cover your children's eyes!
!غطّوا عيون أطفالكم
The last daimyo to serve the Kozuki...
...إنّ آخر دايميو خدم عشيرة الكوزكي
No...
...بل الرجل المرح من بلدة إبيسو
Yasuie!
!ياسويي
Let's sing as I go!
سأغني وأنا أرحل
♪ Here I go! ♪
هيا بنا
Fire!
!أطلقوا
Invade Onigashima!
اذهبوا إلى أونيغاشيما
Avenge your lord!
انتقموا لسيدكم
I await the good news in the afterlife!
سأنتظر الأنباء الجيدة في العالم الآخر
Why would you want to steal this much money?
لماذا حاولتم سرقة كل هذا المال؟
Lord Oden was broke!
!يحتاج أودين-ساما للمال
If you're gonna kill us, just do it already...
!لماذا لا تقتلنا فحسب؟
you hedgehog!
!أيها القنفذ
Damn you, Oden. You certainly know how to pick them.
أودين ذاك اتخذ خدمًا غريبين
Listen up!
يا رجال
I am giving you the money you tried to steal.
بإمكانكم أخذ كل المال الذي حاولتم سرقته
Please rethink this, Lord Yasuie!
!تمهل من فضلك يا ياسويي-ساما
We won't be able to sustain Hakumai's finances!
!ستواجه هاكوماي صعوبات مالية هكذا
You can have this too.
بإمكانكم استعمال هذا أيضًا
It is yours!
خذوه
Even more money?!
!مزيد من المال؟
You gotta be kidding me! Is this a trap?!
!لا تكذب أيها الوغد، هذا فخ
Do you love Oden?
هل تحبون أودين؟
Of course! We owe that man our lives and then some!
!بالطبع نحبه، إننا ندين له بحياتنا
– That's right! – Absolutely!
!هذا صحيح
I see...
هكذا إذًا
Then take this money, make yourselves presentable, learn some manners, buy some books, and study!
...في تلك الحالة، سخّروا هذا المال
Having a bunch of lowlife retainers like you would only disgrace Oden!
إن وجود خدمٍ همج مثلكم سيُلحق العار بأودين
He is the man...
...سيصير يومًا
who will one day become the shogun of Wano!
شوغن بلاد وانو
Those who serve him ought to be the best samurai Wano has to offer!
يجب على من يخدمونه أن يكونوا أفضل ساموراي في وانو
Of course, protecting your lord is a must.
حماية سيدكم هو واجبٌ عليكم
The capital city...
عليكم أن تصبحوا حرّاسًا للعاصمة
No, the entire country of Wano will have you as its guardians!
بل عليكم أن تصبحوا حرّاس وانو بأكملها
Got it?!
أهذا مفهوم؟
– Lord Yasuie!
!ياسويي-دونو
Daddy!
!أبي
Otoko...
...أوتوكو
Please forgive me, Otoko...
...سامحيني يا أوتوكو
for leaving you without a father.
لأنني تركتك ورحلت
Daddy!
!أبي
Daddy! Daddy!
!أبي! أبي
That's enough! Hold your fire!
!عظيم، أوقفوا إطلاق النار
Yasu!
!ياسو
They're the peasants from Ebisu Town! Remove the from the capital!
إنهم متسولون من بلدة إبيسو، اطردوهم خارج العاصمة
Lord Yasuie!
!ياسويي-ساما
D-Daddy!
!أ-أبي
Daddy!
!أبي
D... Daddy?
...أ... أبي
Yasu...!
...ياسو
Are you finally dead, Yasuie?!
هل مت أخيرًا يا ياسويي؟
Lord Yasuie...
...ياسويي-ساما
What are they doing?
ما الذي يحدث هنا؟
What...
...ما الذي
in the world...?
يحدث؟
A man is dead.
شخصٌ قد مات هنا
What the hell's so funny?!
!فما المضحك في هذا؟
My daddy is dead!
!مات أبي
Why you little!
...أيتها الـ
Please wait!
!انتظر رجاءً
They're all... crying.
الجميع... يبكون
What?!
ماذا؟
The people of Ebisu Town are always smiling...
إنّ سكان بلدة إبيسو يضحكون دائمًا
because even in times of pain or sorrow...
حتى في ألمهم وحزنهم
you won't see it on their faces.
لا يستطيعون إظهار عواطفهم
All facial expressions other than a smile were taken away from them...
سُلبت منهم جميع عواطفهم باستثناء الضحك
They can no longer do anything but laugh.
كل ما يسعهم فعله هو الضحك
It's the fault of Kaido and Orochi...
...هذا بسبب ما أحضره كايدو وأوروتشي إلى هنا
for bringing smile fruits here!
!"إنها الفاكهة المسماة "سمايل
Flower Capital
عاصمة الزهور
Ebisu Town
بلدة إبيسو
Bakura Town Kuri
بلدة باكورا كوري
Udon
أودون
Prisoners' Quarters Rasetsu Town Flower Capital
معقل السجناء في بلدة راسيتسو عاصمة الزهور
Hakumai Wano
هاكوماي وانو
Shimotsuki Yasuie
شيموتسكي ياسويي (المعروف لاحقًا بتونوياسو) دايميو هاكوماي
Flower Capital Entrance
مدخل عاصمة الزهور
Hakumai Wano
هاكوماي وانو